[{"question": "Which matplotlib function plots a vertical line at a given x-coordinate?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "plt.axhline(x)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "plt.axvline(x)", "correct": true}, {"answer": "plt.plot(x)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "plt.vert(x)", "correct": false}], "tag": "coding matplotlib", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a non-linear equation?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "2x  = 10x^2 - 8", "correct": false}, {"answer": "x^2  = sin(x)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(x^2 - 5x + 6) / (x - 3) = 0", "correct": true}, {"answer": "x + sin(x) = 0", "correct": false}], "tag": "nla", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "How many solutions does the equation '2x^2 - x - 15 = 0' have?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "2", "correct": true}, {"answer": "3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "0", "correct": false}], "tag": "nla", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "Newton-Raphson method does not always work because", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "the initial guess needs to be right", "correct": false}, {"answer": "the first derivative can be discontinuous at the root", "correct": false}, {"answer": "the first derivative can be undefined at the root", "correct": false}, {"answer": "all of the above", "correct": true}], "tag": "nla newton_raphson", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "<p>What will be the output of f(5, p = 2), where:</p>\n<pre><code>def f(x, p = 10):\n    z = x*p\n\n    print(z)\n</code></pre>", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "10", "correct": true}, {"answer": "Error", "correct": false}, {"answer": "50", "correct": false}, {"answer": "20", "correct": false}], "tag": "functions coding", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "Which of the following finds the 3rd derivative of a function f at the point x0, using scipy.misc.derivative?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "derivative(f, x0, 3)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(derivative(f, x0, 1))^3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "derivative(f, x0, 1, 3)", "correct": true}, {"answer": "None of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "At the solution, the function 'f' in fsolve(f, 5) should return", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "0", "correct": true}, {"answer": "5", "correct": false}, {"answer": "1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "True ", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "<p>What would be the signature of fsolve() where the objective function is:</p>\n<pre><code>def f(x, P):\n    p1, p2 = P\n    return p1*x + p2\n</code></pre>", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "fsolve(f, x0, (p1, p2))", "correct": false}, {"answer": "fsolve(f(p1, p2), x0)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "fsolve(f(P), x0)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "fsolve(f, x0, P)", "correct": true}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "What would be the value of sol.x, when \"sol = fsolve(f, x0, full_output = 1)\" returns the status not equal to 1?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "The result of the last iteration", "correct": true}, {"answer": "0", "correct": false}, {"answer": "1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "The solution", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}, {"question": "What will be the output of:<br><br>[x for x in range(0, 10) if x % 2 == 0]", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "[0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "np.array([0, 2, 4, 6, 8])", "correct": false}, {"answer": "[0, 2, 4, 6, 8]", "correct": true}, {"answer": "[2, 4, 6, 8, 10]", "correct": false}], "tag": "lists coding", "lecture_file": "07_nla_1"}]